# **JOHN**

# **MARCOS**

Senior Full Stack Developer

#### **Contact**

#### Address:

Ανδρούτσου Οδυσσέα 8,Piraeus Greece

#### Phone:

+44 131 496 0654

#### Github:

https://github.com/manager428

#### **Email:**

johnmrocs428@gmail.com

#### Skype:

live:.cid.314ff7cc340ea4f6

#### WebSite:

https://manager428.github.io/

## Languages

English, Greek

#### **Education**

May 2010 – Sep 2014 University of Piraeus

- Bachelor of Science
- Academic Excellence in Computer Science
- Take third place at ACM, part of ICPC in 2014

#### **Hobbies**

- Football
- Art drawing

# **Summary**

Senior Software Developer with 8+ years of experience. Experienced with numerous software technologies focusing on web and blockchain development. Provide high-quality code and power communication. Eager to support building an impeccable online reputation by providing high-level customer support for startups and firms.

## **Skill Highlights**

- Python/Django
- Node/Express
- PHP/Laravel/Shopify
- Ruby on Rails
- Vue/Nuxt.js
- React/Next.js
- Angular
- HTML/CSS
- Bash

- Web3.js
- Solidity
- Ethers.js
- Rust
- Web Scraping
- Smart contract
- Docker
- AWS
- CI/CD

## **Experience**

# **Full Stack Developer** Feb 2021 – Present *Upwork, Freelancer*

- Developed smart contracts from scratch and passed the audit from SlowMist.
- Implemented NFT fractionalization so that users are able to co-won NFT and decide further steps like sale, auction, airdrop together.
- Ecommerce websites using Woocommerce and Shopify.
- Frontend development using React, Vue, Angular.
- Experience in AWS, GCP, Docker, Azure to deploy Python/Django and MERN, MEVN, MEAN projects.

# **Full Stack Developer** Feb 2017 – Jan 2021 *Ratio Finance Houston, United States*

- Slashed payroll/benefits administration costs 30% by negotiating pricing and fees, while ensuring the continuation and enhancements of services.
- Built test cases for frontend and backend.
- Designed and Developed SaaS platform about Generation Marketing with Django.
- Participate in the full lifecycle of development for company web application using Django.
- Implemented transaction with Google Ads API Service to advertise apartments
- Fixed bugs and revamped functionality and speed of several websites.
- Integrated Auth0 API and SendGrid API using python.

#### **Experience**

Senior Full Stack Developer Nov 2015 – Feb 2017

#### Jamis, Edinburgh, United Kingdom

- Developed an E-commerce platform using React for frontend and NodeJS for backend.
- Developed Responsive Websites that could be served by desktop, Tablets and mobile devices using React.js.
- Integrated payment system for product checkout using Authorize, pet payment API.
- Worked with JEST unit test framework to write unit tests for JavaScript code.
- Worked closely with the back-end team to display data using the Custom Components, library components, Redux, Redux-Saga.
- Worked with backend engineers to optimize existing API calls to create efficiencies by deprecating unneeded API calls.
- Involved in all agile ceremonies like Daily stand-ups, Backlog pointing sessions, Planning sessions, retrospection, etc.
- Implemented various screens for the frontend using React.js and used various predefined components from NPM(Node Package Manager) and redux library.
- Interacted with the Testing Team, Scrum Masters and Business Analysts to fix issues.

# **Past Projects**

#### https://www.casamona.com/

- Real Estate website developing.
- SaaS platform Generation Marketing.
- Frontend-React.
- Backend-Django Rest Framework.

## https://www.childrenscolorado.org/

- Hospital System.
- Frontend-React/TypeScript.
- Backend-ASP.NET.

## https://app.defira.com/

• BlockChain, Solidity, Web3.js , React, Next.js...

## https://www.egypttoursplus.com/

- Travel Website.
- Used PHP WordPress, ...

## https://musicengine.top/

- Social Music site.
- Frontend-Vue/Nuxt
- Backend-PHP/Laravel
- Social API using(Google API, Twitter API, Facebook API ...)

## https://bublr.co/

- Chatting Website.
- React, Node, Next.js
- Python Django
- Google API, Auth0

# https://www.novos.gg/

- Game Website.
- Frontend-Vue
- Backend-PHP/Laravel